他们在别的国家  这怎么可能
They're in another country. How is that possible?
不知道  但显然
We don't know, but clearly
绑匪受雇于他人
the kidnappers were working for outside interests.
电话里的声音已被确定为埃及人
The voices on the call have been identified as Egyptian.
这起绑架不是为了赎金
This isn't a kidnapping for ransom,
对吗
Is it?
他们为什么在巴黎
Why are they in Paris?
我不知道
I don't know.
他们把你女儿带到那里
They took your daughter there,
还带走了我女儿  肯定是有原因的
and my daughter along with her. There must be a reason.
我不知道
I don't know!
他们在掩饰踪迹  为什么
They are covering their tracks. Why?
求你了
Please.
我们的女儿也在他们手上
They have our daughter, too.
给他们看素描图
Show them the sketch.
在女孩们被绑后
A neighbor spotted this man
有邻居看到这个男人
coming out of the farmhouse driveway
从农舍的车道上出来
after the girls were taken.
你们有谁认识他吗
Do either of you recognize him?
不  不认识
No, he's not familiar.
我们下一步怎么做
So what's our next step?
视频电话是通过手机通信网络打出的
The skype call was made over a cellular data network,
我们已将信号锁定在
so we have isolated the signal
一片30平方公里的区域内
to a 30-square-kilometer area.
30平方公里就是整个巴黎
30-square kilometers is the whole city.
我知道
I know.
但希望  通过分析视频
But hopefully, an analysis of the video
可以找到她们所在地的线索
will give us a clue as to where they're being held.
与此同时  我们会联系大使馆
In the meantime, we're reaching out to the embassy to estab--
联系  什么意思
Reaching out? What does that mean?
在进一步行动前
There are certain protocols we have to follow
要遵循一些程序  得到一些许可
before we can move forward, permissions we have to get.
这需要多长时间
And how long will that take?
最多一到两天
A day or two at the most.
一到...
A day or...
我们的女儿现在就被他们扣着
Our daughters are out there right now.
她们现在就需要我们去营救
They need our help right now.
如果你想救女儿
If you want to help your daughter,
就得有耐心
you're gonna have to be patient.
她在电话里好害怕
She sounded so scared.
和她小时候一样
I could hear it in her voice,
我可以从她的声音听出来
just like when she was a little girl.
我却无能为力
And there was nothing I could do.
她安然无恙  卡塞尔
She wasn't hurt, Castle.
这点很重要
That's what matters.
这是我们坚持下去的动力
That's what we hold on to.
我只想让她回家
I just want her home.
我们还没有放弃
We're not giving up yet.
绑匪打电话给艾尔玛提了条件
They just called El-Masri with terms.
太快了  我们不可能及时部署好
It's too soon. We can't be in position in time.
我不在乎  我要把她赎回来
I don't care. I'm getting her back.
-绑匪怎么说  -赎金要求
- What did they say? - It was a ransom demand.
支付反穆巴拉克组织1500万欧元
$15 million euro-- from anti-mubarak dissidents.
三小时后以钱换人
They set an exchange three hours from now.
在哪换
Where?
巴黎塞纳河的下游
In Paris down by the seine.
艾尔玛先生  你必须让我联系
Mr. El-masri, you have to let me contact
-有关当局  -不
- the local authorities. - No!
他们说的很清楚
They were clear.
报警的话  我女儿就没命了
They see police, my daughter dies.
我们会交赎金救她
We'll pay to get her back.
他们
Did they...
他们有没有说阿丽克西斯
Did they say anything about Alexis?
在安瓦尔的坚持下
Anwar insisted,
他们同意释放两个女孩子
and they've agreed to release both our daughters.
如果我欠你...
If there is anything I owe you...
你不欠我什么
You owe me nothing.
如果不报警  那么谁去交赎金
If the police aren't involved, then who's making the drop?
我妻子的妹妹住在巴黎
My wife has a sister living in paris.
她的丈夫会去赎人
Her husband will do the exchange.
失陪了  我们有很多电话要打
Now if you'll excuse us, we have many calls to make.
谢谢
Thank you.
只能祈祷这些人言而有信了
Just pray these men are honorable.
塞纳河那段有监控摄像头
There are security cameras covering that portion of the Seine.
至少我们可以调出画面
At the very least, maybe we can get a tap in,
看看绑架犯是谁
see who these guys are.
长官  有实时画面了
Sir, we're live.
有动静吗
Any activity?
目前没有
It looks deserted so far.
那里
There.
能推近镜头吗
Can you get any closer?
就是他  这是艾哈迈德
That's him. That's Ahmed.
看起来好不真实
This doesn't even seem real.
就像电视节目
It's like some kind of show.
艾哈迈德
Ahmed!
给巴黎警方打电话  快
Get the Paris police on the phone. Now.
不不不  等等
No, no, no, no! Wait. Wait.
不要啊
No. No!
她们在哪  孩子们在哪
Where-- where are they? Where are the girls?
他找到她了  她安全了
He has her. She's safe.
阿丽克西斯呢
Where's Alexis?
哈里斯探员刚问过莎拉
Agent Harris just spoke with Sara.
她说那次企图逃跑之后她俩就失散了
She and Alexis were separated after the escape attempt.
那是她最后一次见到阿丽克西斯
And that was the last time that she saw her.
他们已经得其所愿  她没价值了
They got what they wanted. She's of no value anymore.
你并不确定
You don't know that.
我确定
Yes, I do.
你去哪
Where you going?
告诉我妈妈  她还不知道
To tell my mother. She doesn't know yet.
我跟你去
I'll go with.
不用了
No.
我要自己来
I need to do this alone.
也许卡塞尔说得对
Castle may be right.
莎拉才是目标
Sara was the objective.
阿丽克西斯现在是拖油瓶了
Alexis is just a liability now.
那他们为什么不一起放了她
Then why didn't they bring her to the exchange?
跟当初绑架她是一个道理  她是谈判的筹码
The same reason they took her-- a bargaining chip,
万一出什么事  她可以保他们平安
insurance in case something went wrong.
现在他们已经不需要她了
Insurance they don't need anymore.
我们会继续追查
We'll keep moving forward.
但也不能抱太大希望
But we have to manage expectations now.
哈里斯探员  我不会降低期望的
Agent Harris, I'm not gonna manage expectations.
我会去破一件凶杀案
I'll be solving a murder.
绑架两个女孩的人  罗杰·汉森
The girls' kidnapper Roger Henson
在死前曾受到折磨
was tortured and killed,
很可能是雇佣他的人干的
most likely be the people that hired him.
找到那些人  就能找到阿丽克西斯
We find those people, we will find Alexis.
卡塞尔  又是我
Castle, it's me again.
你听到留言能给我回个电话吗
Can you just call me when you get this?
他还不接电话
He still not answering?
是啊
No.
-谢了  -不客气
- Thanks. - You're welcome.
那个死者有什么发现吗
Any luck on the dead guy?
完全查不到汉森的记录
Henson's been... completely off the grid.
连地址都查不到
I can't even find a known address.
我不明白的是
All right, here's what I don't get--
一个混得一般的毒品走私贩
how does a mid-level narcotics smuggler
怎么会和一群中东激进分子勾搭到一起
get hooked up with a bunch of middle-eastern radicals?
埃斯波  我都不知从哪查起
Espo, I can't find a connection
要怎么找其中的关联啊
if I don't even know where to start.
你们飞机查得怎么样了
How are you guys doing on the planes?
我和莱恩查了从纽约出发去奥尔巴尼的
Ryan and I have been through every flight plan
每一架私人飞机的飞行计划
of every private jet that's departed from here to Albany,
只有两架会去法国
and only a couple of 'em filed flight plans for France.
目前看来  都是合法飞行
So far, they all seem legit.
我和莱恩明早再扩大搜索范围
So Ryan and I are gonna expand our search in the morning.
凯特
Kate.
怎么了
What?
你该走了
You should go.
他需要你
He needs you.
凯特
Kate.
谢天谢地  有消息吗
Thank God. Is there any news?
还没有  不过我们正在全力调查
Uh, no, not yet, but we are doing everything that we can.
理查德呢
Well, where's Richard?
我还以为他和你在一起
I thought that he was with you.
没有  他说和你一起查案呢
No. He told me he was gonna be with you, working on the case.
玛莎  我一整天都没见到他
Martha, I haven't seen him all day.
不是吧
Oh, no.
怎么了
What?
不要啊
No.
不见了
It's gone.
什么不见了
What's gone?
太傻了  这个笨蛋
Oh, it's so stupid. It's just stupid.
玛莎  怎么了
Martha, what's going on?
接电话  快接电话
Pick up. Pick up. Pick up. Pick up.
我是卡塞尔
Castle.
理查德  你在哪
Richard, where are you?
我和贝克特在警局  怎么了
I'm at the precinct with Beckett. Why?
别骗我了  理查德
Don't lie to me, Richard.
贝克特在这里  你的护照不见了
Beckett is here. Your passport is gone.
你到底要干什么
Now what the hell do you think you're doing?
救我女儿
Getting my daughter back.
巴黎  他去巴黎干什么
Paris? What the hell is he doing in paris?
他自认为可以找到她
He thinks that he can find her.
怎么  他当自己是连姆·尼森了
What, so he's Liam Neeson now?
连姆·尼森  他连艾什莉·贾德都比不上
Liam Neeson? The dude's barely Ashley Judd.
以他现在的状态  谁知道会干出什么来
Look, in the state that he's in, who knows what he's capable of?
但他说他认识帮得上忙的人
But he says that he knows someone that can help.
你要去找他吗
You gonna go after him?
浪费一整天飞过去
And a lose a day flying out there
再浪费一整天
and another one tracking him down
在一个我无权无势的地方找他
in a place that I don't have jurisdiction or authority?
不
No.
他...
Look, he's...
他在做父亲该做的
He's acting like a father,
我要做警察该做的
And... I have to act like a cop.
你们能再去找一下联调局
Can you circle back with the Feds?
让他们扩大搜索  查找所有
Have 'em widen the search to any private jets
飞入欧洲的私人飞机
flying out to anywhere in Europe.
莱恩  罗杰·汉森我查不下去了
And, Ryan, I'm hitting a wall with Roger Henson.
你可以问问你缉毒组的老朋友吗
You think you can reach out to your guys in narcotics?
或许他们知道些传闻
Maybe they heard something on the streets.
好
Yeah.
我不知道卡塞尔以为自己认识谁
Look, you guys, I don't know who Castle thinks he knows.
但是我们得先找到他女儿
But let's find his daughter
免得他做出什么蠢事害死自己
before he does something stupid and gets himself killed.
谢谢  科莱特
Merci, Colette.
如果你离开你男朋友...
Et si jamais vous quittez votre petit ami...
理查德
Richard?
你好啊  加斯顿
Hello, Gaston.
理查德  我真替你难过
Richard, I am so terribly sorry.
如果我能做什么
If there's anything I can do...
你还给国防部做顾问  对吗
You're still working as an advisor to the minister of defense, right?
对  但我跟警察没什么交情
Yes, but that gives me very little pull with the police nationale.
但是我能帮你问问
Uh, I could make inquiries, though.
谢谢你
No. Um... I appreciate it.
我不需要人来搪塞我
I'm not really looking for a bureaucratic runaround.
你在为我前几部
When you were advising me
德里克里·斯道姆小说做顾问时
on those last few Derrick Storm novels,
曾提到一个法国政府无法进行正式行动时
you mentioned a man that the french government would sometimes hire
便会雇佣的人
when they couldn't afford to take official action.
里奇  那是悄悄话
Ricky, I told you that in confidence.
他是真有其人吗
But he exists?
坐在你桌子后面安全地写书
It is one thing to write about these characters
那是一回事
from the safety of your own desk.
但这样的人
But men like this,
你不会想认识他们这种人
they are not the kind of people you ever want to know.
碧翠斯  现在多大了  14吗
Beatrice--she must be, what, 14 now?
帕特里斯有9岁了
Patrice going on 9?
我想让你想想
I want you to think about how it feels
你抱着她们的感觉
when you hug them,
你回家时看着她们眼睛的感觉
the look in their eye when you come home.
现在想想她们失踪的感觉
And now imagine them gone.
他可不便宜
He's expensive.
我不在乎
I don't care.
加斯顿  求你了
Gaston, please.
盯住手机
Stay close to your phone.
贝克特
Yo, Beckett.
他们没飞去巴黎  至少没直接去
They didn't fly to Paris, at least not at first.
联邦航空局记录一架猎鹰
F.A.A. shows a dassault falcon
在泰特波罗机场出发飞往布鲁塞尔
departing Teterboro to Brussels
时间是绑架发生18小时之后
18 hours after the girls were taken.
这架飞机被指定为医用飞机
The plane was then designated a medical angel flight,
用于运输两位亟待器官移植的年轻女子
transporting two young women awaiting organ transplant
从布鲁塞尔飞往巴黎
from Brussels to Paris.
阿丽克西斯和莎拉
Alexis and Sara.
法国移民局检查了飞机和两个女孩
French immigration met the plane and processed the girls
然后送她们上了救护车
before they were loaded onto an ambulance.
她们当时都昏迷不醒
They were both unconscious at the time.
他们就是这么做到的
That's how they did it.
能查到这架飞机什么资料
What do we know about the plane?
它属于一个俄罗斯寡头政治集团的成员
It's owned by one of those Russian oligarchs--
弗拉基米尔·阿布拉姆维奇
Uh, Vladimir Abramovich.
他跟艾尔玛家什么关系
And how is he connected to the El-Masris?
没关系
He's not.
其实他可能根本毫无牵连
In fact, it's possible he's not even involved.
他的飞机是在巴黎维修
His plane was in Paris under repairs.
他的人根本不知道飞机被盗了
And none of his people even knew it was taken.
他们偷了架飞机
These people stole a jet?
就为了个人质交换
For a simple hostage exchange?
这说不通啊
That doesn't add up.
我跟我缉毒组的人谈过了
Hey, so I talked to my guys in narcotics.
他们似乎并不知道
Now they didn't seem to know much
汉森最近都做了什么
about what Henson had been into recently
或是他住在那儿
or where he'd been living,
但他们知道我们不知道的
but they did know something that we didn't.
汉森有个女朋友
Henson had a girlfriend.
"复仇是我的"  主说
"'vengeance is mine,' sayeth the lord.
"我会报复的"
'I will repay.'"
但是有时候
But sometimes,
主需要一点点帮助
the lord needs a little help, huh?
谢谢你能来
Thank you for coming.
先别谢我
Don't thank me yet.
我的条件
My terms.
先付一半  我找到她再付一半
Half now. Half when I find her.
你能找到她吗
Can you find her?
能
Yes.
但我未必能找到活着的她
But I don't promise to find her alive.
那是我难以掌控的
That, I'm afraid, is out of my control.
我们从何做起呢
Where do we start?
我知道有一段她给你打电话的录音
I understand there is a recording of a call she made to you.
你怎么
How did you...
没错  是有段录音
Yeah, there's a recording.
给我一份
I'll need a copy.
上面没有能够表明她在哪的东西
There's nothing on it that indicates where she is.
谁告诉你的
And who told you that?
联调局
The FBI.
那你就感谢上帝我不是联调局的
Well, then you thank god I'm not the FBI.
来吧
Come.
去哪里
Where are we going?
见个朋友
To see a friend.
你好  亨利
Bonjour, Henri.
你好
Bonjour.
你就是卡塞尔先生吧
Monsieur Castle, I presume.
对
Yeah.
你是哪位
And--and you are?
我们管他叫灰褐色
We call him le taupe.
那块痣
The mole.
放轻松
Detendu, huh?
-不错  -什么
- Mm. Pas mal. - What?
他说你紧张  他能听到你急促的心跳声
He says you're nervous. He can hear your heart?
窗外有什么
What's out-- what's outside the window?
什么都没有  我看不见
Nothing. Nothing. I can't see anything.
窗户都被遮住了
The windows are covered up.
他们来了  他们发现我们跑了
They're comming. They're coming. They found out we're gone.
宝贝  快跑  快跑出去
Baby, get of there. Get out of there now.
我说过了  上面什么都没有
I told you, there's nothing on there.
没有可听可看的线索
Nothing to see or hear.
你是用肉眼看在聆听
Ah. You listen with your eyes. Shh.
那里  听到了吗
There. Hear that?
没
No.
就在那里
Right there.
教堂的钟声
Church bells.
圣佐治教堂  第16街上
St. George's, In the 16th.
从钟声推断
From the sound of it,
她在六个
she's, uh, six,
或约八个街区开外
maybe eight blocks away.
而且她所在的大楼里有家餐馆
And there's a restaurant in the building she's in.
你怎么知道的
How can you tell that?
声音  卡塞尔先生  像是各种指纹
Sounds, Mr. Castle, are like fingerprints.
没有两个是相同的
No two are alike.
那种杂声
Ah, that hum?
来自餐馆的通风系统
It's from a restaurant ventilation system,
商业级的
Commercial grade,
还有
and, uh...
有待维修
It needs servicing.
你多久没睡觉了
When was the last time you slept?
不知道  我没事
I-I don't know. I'm good.
不  这需要些时间
No, this will take some time.
我们有发现时  我会叫醒你
I will wake you when we find something, huh?
窗外  窗外有什么
What's out-- what's outside the window?
他们来了
They're coming.
他们来了  他们发现我们跑了
They're coming. They found out we're gone.
宝贝  快跑  快跑出去
Baby, get out of there. Get out of there now.
迪嘉莫女士
Ms. DeGarmo,
我再问你一遍
I'm gonna ask you again.
对于罗杰·汉森的被杀  你还有什么要说的
What else can you tell me about Roger Henson's murder?
我无可奉告
I don't have to tell you nothing.
我知道我的权利  你不能留我
I know my rights. You can't keep me here.
他死了
He's dead,
被拷打了
tortured.
我只想找出罪魁祸首
I'm just trying to find the people that did it to him.
听着  贱人
Listen, bitch,
我不和警察啰嗦
I don't talk to cops.
给我去找律师  然后给我滚
Now go get me my lawyer and then go to hell--
你搞得清状况吗
Do you have any idea what this is all about?!
你以为我是那种因为你藏毒
You think I'm some beat cop
就逮捕你的刑警吗
busting you on possession charges?
我搭档的女儿失踪了
My partner's daughter is missing,
而你
And you...
在干扰我破案
are in my way.
你不肯配合警方
Now you don't talk to cops?
我今天不是警察  亲爱的
I'm not a cop today, honey.
他在为谁做事
Who was he working for?
他没说
He didn't say.
这人是谁
Who's this guy?
不知道
I don't know.
什么
What?
可罗杰半夜会接到奇怪的电话
But Roger got strange calls in the middle of the night.
带口音的人
People with accents.
哪种口音
What kind of accents?
-外国口音  -他用的哪部电话
- Foreign. - What phone did he use?
他没给我号码
He didn't give me the number!
好  我信你
Good. I believe you.
现在给我他家地址
Now you're gonna give me his address.
看来有人先到一步
Looks like somebody got here first.
这些人雇他绑架这些姑娘们
These people hired him to kidnap those girls.
那他们为什么拷打杀掉他
So why would they torture and murder him?
为什么把这里翻个底朝天
Why would they toss this place?
或许不是同一帮人干的
Maybe it wasn't the same guys.
还会是谁
Who else is it gonna be?
去拜访一下街坊邻居  问问他们看到什么
Check with the neighbors. See if they saw anything.
好
Yeah.
贝克特  电脑
Beckett, computer.
交给技术部
Get it to Tech.
让他们仔细研究  给我点线索
Have them tear it apart. Find me something,
什么都行
Anything.
怎么了
What's going on?
你有所发现了吗
You found something?
或许吧
Maybe.
吸音板
Acoustic tiles,
办公地点  接近屋顶
office space, close to a rooftop--
可能找到地方了
Might fill the bill.
我也去
I'm coming.
不不不  可能不是那地方
No, no, no. It might not be the place.
我不介意
I don't care.
可能就是那地方
It could be the place.
我女儿  我付钱
My daughter, my money.
我要去
I'm coming.
他们就关在这儿
They were here.
现在不在了
Not anymore.
这不是一般绑匪的手法
This is not the work of typical kidnappers.
清理得很干净
The place is clean.
太干净了
It's too clean.
这是情报人员的手法
This is tradecraft.
你说的是间谍吗
Tradecraft as in spies?
干这事的人一定受过情报训练
Whoever is behind this has intelligence training.
他们没留丝毫线索
They left no trace.
那我们怎么找
So how do we find 'em?
你说你可以找到他们
You said you could find them--
他们在监听
They're listening.
如果警察查到这儿了
So if the cops find this place,
他们仍可以快警察一步
they stay ahead of the investigation.
到底是什么人
Who are these people?
我们来查查
Let's find out.
我知道你在
I know you're out there.
我知道你在听  所以知道我不是警察
I know you're listening, so you know I'm not a cop.
我对你  你的理由以及法律都没兴趣
I'm not interested in you, your cause, or the law.
我们只要那女孩
All we want is the girl.
你已经得到你要的了
You got what you wanted.
她现在对你没意义了  但对我却不是
Now she's meaningless to you, but not to me.
所以你要是聪明的  就打过来
So if you're smart, you call,
我们谈谈价钱
we discuss terms.
但你要是犯傻
But if you are stupid,
那我就会来找你
then I will come for you.
但愿你有声音识别系统
I expect by now you have run voice recognition,
这样你就知道我是谁  我可是出了名的
so you know who I am, you know my reputation,
让我找到你  就让你见识我的厉害
and you know what I will do when I find you.
选择权在你手上
The choice is yours.
喂
Oui.
绿色走廊  七点钟[法语]
La coulee verte, sept huers.
一个人来[法语]
Venez seul.
别带她爹来[法语]
Sans la pare.
他是在说
"Sans la pere"?
"别带她爹来"吗
Without the father?
你不觉得这是好事吗
Don't you see? This is good news.
他们想谈判  这说明她处境安全
They want to negotiate. It means she's safe.
你不能不带我去谈判
You're not having that meeting without me.
你情绪不稳定
You are emotionally compromised.
这会让他们觉得你像只野兽
that makes you like an animal to them--
危险而无法预测
Unpredictable and dangerous.
卡塞尔先生
Monsieur Castle...
我就是干这个的
This is what I do.
这就是你雇我的原因
It's what you pay me for.
让我去见他们
Now let me meet with them.
让我去和他们谈价钱吧
Let me negotiate the terms.
当然  他们会要更多的钱
Oh, and of course they will ask for more money.
我想知道
I need to know...
你能付多少
How much can you afford?
贝克特
Yo, Beckett.
亨森的邻居看见有人从他家出来
One of Henson's neighbors saw someone leaving his apartment
两天前的事
two days back.
我们刚得到画像
We just got the sketch.
正是那个从亨森死亡的农场
That's the same dude who was spotted leaving the farmhouse
走出来的人
where Henson's body was found.
他先是拷打了亨森
First he tortures Henson,
然后又搜遍了他家  这是为何
and then he trashes his place. Why?
亨森的硬盘处理得怎样了
Where are you with Henson's hard drive?
全被删掉了
It's been erased,
只剩下应用程序
and not with commercial software.
你能提取出信息吗
Were you able to pull anything from it?
我尽力吧
I'll do what I can,
但你别抱太大希望
but I wouldn't get your hopes up.
去吧  我们得查出他想找什么
Do it. We gotta figure out what he was looking for.
别担心
Don't worry.
亨利总是能搞定
Henri always comes through.
他怎么还没回来
Shouldn't he be back by now?
回来了
He is.
她在那儿吗
Was she there?
是的  而且她情况安好
Yes, and she is safe.
这是今天的报纸
This is today's paper.
他们为什么要抓她
Why did they take her?
顺手抓的  但他们同意放了她
It was convenient, but they've agreed to let her go.
什么时候
When?
今天晚些时候  在枫丹白露的森林里
Later today, in the forest of Fontainebleau.
有时间让你筹款
It will give you time to get the money together.
贝克特探长
Detective Beckett!
亨森是在找这个
Henson was looking at these.
都是偷拍的照片
Surveillance photos.
天啊  是阿丽克西斯
Oh, god. Alexis.
她不是在错的时间出现在错的地点
She wasn't at the wrong place at the wrong time.
她本来就是目标
She was the target.
阿丽克西斯在哪儿  我没见到她
Where's Alexis? I don't see her.
冷静
Stay calm.
不不不  这不对劲
No, no, no. This isn't right.
不对劲
It's not right.
别动
Don't move.
你出卖我  为什么
You're selling me out? Why?
为了保命  我只好背信弃义
I value my life more than my word.
如果我知道是谁绑架了你的女儿
If I had known who was really holding your daughter,
知道你女儿是谁
who your daughter really is...
我女儿是谁  我糊涂了
Who she really is? Look, I-I don't understand.
我根本不会接下这份活儿
I would never have taken the job.
她只是个普通人
She's nobody.
等等
Attendez.
我的钱
Mon paiement?
等等  好吧  等等
Wait. Okay, wait.
你们想要什么
Just... what do you want?
如果我要你死
If I'd wanted you dead,
你早死了
You'd be dead.
你就是画像上的人  你去过农场
You're the guy in the sketch. You were at the farmhouse.
没错
That's right.
你那朋友很厉害
Your friend there was pretty good,
但是对付这些人还是不够火候
but a bit out of his league.
我一点也不奇怪他会出卖你
I am not surprised that he crossed to the other side.
你知道这到底是怎么回事
You know what's going on here?
你知道我女儿在哪
You--do you know where my daughter is?
听我说  我们已经暴露了
Look, we're exposed here.
得赶紧离开这儿
We gotta go now.
离开  你说什么呢  去哪儿
Go? What are you talking about? Go where?
去安全的地方  快上车
Somewhere safe. Get in the car.
你得先告诉我这是怎么回事
No, not until you tell me what's going on.
贝克特  真高兴你打来了
Beckett, I am so glad you called.
卡塞尔  阿丽克西斯不是顺带被绑走的
Castle, Alexis wasn't taken by accident.
她才是真正的目标  他们要绑架的是她
She was the target. They wanted her.
听我说  我
Listen, i--
你这是干嘛  那部手机要200块呢
What are you doing?! That was a $200 phone.
他们就是用手机来追踪你的
And that's how they track you.
现在赶紧给我上车
Now get in the car.
我才不会上车呢
Hey, I am not getting in the car.
别傻了  我是好人
Oh, don't be an idiot. I'm the good guy.
你觉得我会相信你吗
Oh, you expect me to trust you?
你现在不是还活着吗  对吧
Well, you're still alive, aren't you?
你能怎么办
What are you gonna do,
跟这群死人待在这里吗
Stay out here in the woods with all the dead guys?
好吧
Fine.
我上车
I'll get in the car.
考虑到你对那200块钱的手机
Given how you're feeling so bad
都心疼的要命
about your 200-buck phone,
你还是把那装了300万美元的箱子捡起来吧
You might want to pick up that $3-million briefcase.
别弄丢了
Take it with you.
起码告诉我你的名字吧
At least tell me your name.
亨特  杰克森·亨特
Hunt. Jackson Hunt.
像是个假名字
That sounds made up.
是假的
It is.
能不能告诉我这到底是怎么回事儿
Hey, could someone just please tell me what's going on?
为什么我会在这儿
Why am I here?
这里暂时是安全的
We should be safe here for now.
你从哪弄到的这些
Where did you get these?
这不重要
That's not important.
重要的是我们得把她救出来
You know what's important, is we get her back.
我根本都不认识你  这关你什么事
Well, I don't even know you. Why would you care?
这是我的任务  我是受命于人
It's my job. I was sent.
受命于谁  艾尔玛一家吗
By whom, the El-masris?
管他是谁呢
What's the difference?
你得告诉我是谁雇佣了你
You need to tell me who hired you
还有这些人为什么要绑走我的女儿
and why these people took my daughter.
找你的
That's yours.
你不接吗
You want to get it?
怎么会是找我的  你已经把我的打烂了
How is it mine? You shot mine.
我复制了一个  我就是这样找到你的
It's a clone. That's how I tracked you.
它们的区别是这部手机是安全的
The difference is that that one's secure.
可能是贝克特打来的
It's probably Beckett.
你应该让她知道你安全了
You ought to let her know you're safe.
不是贝克特  是当地的号码
It's not Beckett. It's a local number.
是阿丽克西斯
Alexis.
是阿丽克西斯吗
Alexis?
不是的  卡塞尔先生
I'm afraid not, Mr. Castle.
不过她在我手里
But I am the one holding her.
如果你还在意她的生命的话
If you value her life,
你最好把电话交给站在你身边的那个人
you will give the phone to the man standing next to you,
那个在树林里大开杀戒的人
the one responsible for all the bloodshed in the woods.
什么事
Yeah?
是你
It's you.
这么多年  我终于找到你了
After all these years, it's finally you.
你该放她走了  霍尔科夫
Time to let her go, Volkov.
就像你放走安娜吗
The way you let Anna go?
不  是时候了结这一切了
No. It's time to end things.
一命
A life
抵一命
for a life.
明天早晨6点
Tomorrow, 6:00 a.m.
波旁宫外面
Outside the Palais Bourbon.
如果你来  我就饶了她
If you show, I'll spare her.
但如果你不来
But if you don't,
我就会杀了她
I will put a bullet in her brain instead of yours,
然后我们重新开始
and we start again.
这一切都因为你
This is about you?
是的
Yeah.
我不明白
I don't understand.
这跟阿丽克西斯有什么关系
What does this have to do with Alexis?
他们为什么要抓她
Why would they take her?
因为我大意了
Because I was careless.
不知他通过什么方法
Because somehow he found out
知道了她和你的身份
who she was, who you were,
而且他还知道我会为她挺身而出的
and he knew I'd come for her.
为什么  为什么你会为她挺身而出
Why? Why would you come for her?
因为她是我的孙女
Because she's my granddaughter.
理查德
Richard,
我是你父亲
I'm your father.
你是说你是个间谍
You're telling me you're a spy?
应该说是"情报特工"
"Intelligence asset" is the term.
我老爸是个间谍
My dad's a spy.
我妈知道吗
Does my mom know?
她是怎么跟你说我的
What did she tell you about me?
她说那是个很特别的夜晚
Uh, that it was a special night.
她坠入了爱河
She was in love.
第二天她醒来时  你已经走了
She woke up the next morning, you were gone.
她再也没有见过你
She never saw you again.
是啊  那天晚上
Yeah, that night,
我刚在联合国完成了一项任务
I had just finished a job at the U.N.
至少我认为我完成了
Least I thought I had.
但第二天  形势急转直下
And the next day, things went south.
我不得不赶紧离开
I had to get out of the city fast.
一年之后我才回国
It was a year before I was stateside again.
那时我才知道有了你
That's when I found out about you.
这么多年来  你一直知道我的存在
You've known about me...
我们的存在
about us, all these years,
而你却从来不曾现身
and you never once let us know you were out there?
我的工作就是不能与任何人
What I do means no communication,
有任何关系  任何交流
no relationships, to anyone.
但是  我一直在你左右
But... hey, I've been around.
我们见过面
We've met before.
没错
Yeah.
你十岁的时候
When you were about 10 years old,
你妈妈带你去图书馆
Your mother took you to the library,
当时你正在找一本书
and you were looking for a book and, uh,
我给了你一本
I gave you a copy of, uh--
《皇家赌场》[007原著]
"Casino Royale."
没错
Yeah.
是你
That was you?
是那本书让我立志成为一名作家
That book made me want to become a writer.
我看到你的第一本间谍小说时简直不敢相信
I couldn't believe it when I read your first spy novel.
你还看过我的书
You read my books?
是啊  当你想去中情局调研
Oh, yeah. I greased some wheels at the CIA
查阅资料时
when you were trying to get access
我还帮了点忙呢
to some information for research.
虽然微不足道
I know that's not much,
但那让我...
But for a minute there...
让我有一种为人父的感觉
It made me feel like a father.
我也关心你  关心你妈妈
No, I've been, uh, checking on you and your mom
还有阿丽克西斯
and Alexis
关注着你的一生
your whole lives.
绑架我女儿的人  他是谁
This man who has my daughter, who is he?
乔治·霍尔科夫
Gregor Volkov?
克格勃最令人畏惧的特工
The K.G.B.'s most feared agent.
我杀了他的妻子安娜
I killed his wife Anna,
是一次反情报行动
a counter-intelligence operative,
12年前就在巴黎
12 years ago in an operation here in Paris.
他第一次追杀我时
The first time he came after me,
我把他关进了车臣的监狱  终生监禁
I put him away in a Chechen prison for life.
而他逃了出来
Then... he escaped.
此后  他就想尽办法
And he's been trying to figure out a way
要把我揪出来
to draw me out ever since.
如果这是针对阿丽克西斯
If this was about Alexis,
为什么还要带走另一个女孩
why would he take the other girl?
因为如果他只抓走阿丽克西斯
Because if he just took Alexis,
这就不会成为国际新闻
it wouldn't be international news.
他需要位高权重的人  他要让我知道
He needed somebody high-profile. He needed me to know.
现在他已得偿所愿找到我了
And now he's got me exactly where he wants me.
如果我明天不出现  他就会杀了她
If I don't show up tomorrow, he will kill her.
如果你出现会怎样
And if you do show up?
他会杀了我们两个取乐
He'll kill us both just for fun.
如果你了解我  你知道我会不顾一切
If you know me at all, you know I'll do anything.
那我们唯一的优势就是
Then our only advantage is
霍尔科夫不知道我已经找到他了
Volkov doesn't know I've found him.
他可能会对直接袭击猝不及防
He may not be prepared for a direct assault.
如果我能进入他的地盘
If I can get inside his compound,
我就能救阿丽克西斯出来
I can get Alexis out.
直接袭击
A direct assault?
这是我们最好的机会  她最好的机会
This is our best shot, her best shot.
但我们需要一个战略优势
But we need a tactical advantage.
我一个人做不到
I can't do this alone.
告诉我你需要什么
Tell me what you need.
她被关押的地方
Where she's being held,
有一根为整个房子供能的管道
there's a conduit supplying it
贯穿在污水管道系统
that runs through the old sewer system.
你切断电缆  你就断了他们的电源
You cut those cables, you cut their power.
电灯  警报  摄像头
Lights, alarm, security video--
那根管道是关键
That conduit's the key.
你觉得呢  孩子
What do you say, kid?
你扮演警察已经好几年
You been playing cop for years.
准备好来当次间谍吗
You ready to play spy?
情况怎样
How are we doing?
我就快到了
Yeah, I'm almost there.
你应该看到一个分线箱
You should see a junction box
分出来六根管道
with six conduits coming from it.
我看到了
I see it.
你要找的是从下往上数第三根
The one you want is the third one from the bottom.
找到了
Got it.
像我教你的那样把炸药绕在上面
Wrap the charge around it like I showed you
装上引爆器
and then attach the detonator.
设定了三十秒
All right. I'm setting the detonator for 30 seconds...
计时开始
Now.
不许动
Don't move.
我们可能有麻烦了
We may have a problem.
爸爸
Dad?
Dad.
阿丽克西斯
Alexis?
Alexis.
-爸爸  爸爸  -阿丽克西斯
- Dad. Dad! - Alexis.
阿丽克西斯
Alexis.
你还好吗
You okay?
嗯  不过你来这里干什么
Yeah, but... what are you doing here?
他们也绑架了你吗
Did they kidnap you, too?
是的
Uh... yeah.
试着来救你
Trying to... rescue you.
你不应该来的
You shouldn't be here.
没关系  我们团聚了
Shh. It's okay. We're together now.
会没事的
It's gonna be okay.
你看起来还不错
You--you look good.
你很像你的父亲  卡塞尔先生
You are like your father, Mr. Castle.
不关你的事情也要来插一脚
Getting involved where you don't belong.
他真以为
Did he really think
我会毫无准备吗
I would not prepared for an attack?
爸爸  他在说什么
Dad, what's he talking about?
告诉她
Tell her.
说啊  说出她被绑架的原因
Go on. Tell her why she's here.
你捉住我了
You have me now.
她没有利用价值了  放她走
She's of no use to you. Let her go.
我有了双倍的筹码
When a man doubles his wealth,
为什么要再放弃一半呢
why should he give half of it away?
他带着这个
He had this on him.
是时候做个了断了
Time to end this.
我知道你在这里
I know that you are here.
知道你在附近
I know that you are close.
告诉你
And I want you to know
你儿子在我手上
that I have your son.
给你十秒钟  出现在我手下面前
You have ten seconds to show yourself to my men out front.
投降
Give yourself up...
不然我就杀了他
or I will kill him.
爸爸
Dad.
没事的
It's okay.
十
Ten...
九
Nine...
八
Eight...
-七  -对不起
- Seven... - I'm sorry.
-没事的  -六
- It's all right. - Six...
五
Five...
四
Four...
-三  -你不会杀我儿子的  霍尔科夫
- THREE... - You're not gonna kill my son, Volkov.
不会么
No?
为什么
And why is that?
因为你快要死了
Because you'll be dead.
趴下
Get down.
炸药爆炸之后
Once the charge goes off,
会引起片刻的骚动
there'll be a moment when it all hits the fan.
用这个救她出来
Use this to get her out.
闭上眼睛  亲爱的
Close your eyes, sweetheart.
然后  跑
And then run.
跑
Go.
Let's go.
他的手下会到前厅去
His men will move to the front
跟我交火
to respond to my attack.
你们从后门走
You move to the back,
穿过这些门
through these doors
一路穿过走廊
and right down this corridor.
那他的手下呢
And what about his men?
如果他们阻止我们怎么办
What if they try to stop us?
摆平他们啊
Don't let them.
一直跑到后门
Just keep moving until you hit the back door
因为我会从前门进去
'cause I'll be coming in the front.
一直跑  不要停
Don't stop running, ever...
直到跑到美国大使馆
not until you reach the U.S. Embassy.
你到了大使馆以后
And once you reach the embassy,
找大使馆副馆长吉姆·阿达科特
ask for deputy chief of missions Jim Aldacott.
他会提供给你们官方掩护身份
And he'll provide you both with an official cover story.
事情归到国际刑警和法国警方身上
One that credits Interpol and the French police
不会牵扯到我
and doesn't include me.
那你之后会怎么样
What happens to you after?
假设...  我们都活着
Assuming... we're both not killed,
我会消失
I-I disappear.
不要  我们才
No, but we just--
这是工作  这是我的生活
That's the job. That's my life.
没错  但是  我们才见面
Yeah, but, uh... we just met.
我还有好多事要问你
I mean, I got a lot of questions,
有好多话想说
A lot of things I want to say.
我不  我不
I don't--I don't...
我需要更多时间
I-I need to have more time.
或许改天我们能叙个旧
Maybe we can do that sometime,
改天吧
You know, someday.
我怎么才能知道你有没有脱身
How will I know if you made it?
你没法知道  至少官方渠道不行
Oh, you won't. Not officially at least.
我知道这不好受  理查德
I know this has been tough for you, Richard, and...
我只想你知道  儿子
I just want you to know, son,
我永远为你感到骄傲
I've always been proud of you.
永远
Always.
回家从来没这么开心过
I have never in my life been so happy to be home.
阿门
Amen.
我知道我们不该谈论
I know we're not supposed to talk about
发生的那些事  但是
what really happened, but...
谢谢你
Thank you for everything.
这是老爸应该做的
Hey, it's what fathers do.
你觉得他脱身了吗
You think he made it out?
我希望我知道
I wish I knew.
准备好了吗
You ready?
你们回来了
You're back!
-你们回来了  -回家真好
- You're back! - Ohh. It's great to be home.
很高兴你没事
I'm so glad you're okay.
以后别再像这样撇开我单独行动了
Please don't do anything like that again without me.
不会了
I won't.
没事了奶奶  我没事
It's okay, gram. I'm okay.
宝贝
Honey, hi.
过来
Come here.
你太有才了
You are brilliant.
太有才  大家肯定都饿昏了吧
Just bril--everybody must be starving.
来  我做了早点
Come on. I've made breakfast.
妈妈  这是什么
Mother, what's this?
你的邮件  早上到的
Oh, it came for you this morning.
怎么了  很重要吗
Why, is it important?
妈妈
Mom...
我想告诉你一些事
There's something I want to tell you.